Guide to the J. B. Matthews Papers, 1862-1986 and undated
J. B. Matthews papers 1862-1986 and undated
- Vertical Files Series, ca. 1920s-1980s Part II
  - Conference of Studio Unions, 1947 (Folder 4)
  - Conference of The Emergency Trade Union Committee, 1949 (Folder 5)
  - Conference of The Professions, 1938 (Folder 6)
  - Conference of Young Women, 1945 (Folder 7)
  - Conference on China and The Far East, 1946 (Folder 8)
  - Conference on Civil Rights, 1940 (Folder 9)
  - Conference on Constitutional Liberties in America, 1939 (Folder 10)
  - Conference on Consumer Education, 1941 (Folder 11)
  - Conference on Democracy and Autonomy in The CIO, 1949 (Folder 12)
  - Conference on Fair Employment Practices, 1950 (Folder 13)
  - Conference on National Defense and WPA, 1941 (Folder 14)
  - Conference on Pan American Democracy, 1938 (Folder 15)
  - Conference on Peaceful Alternatives to The Atlantic Pact, 1949 (Folder 16)
  - Conference on Puerto Rico's Right to Freedom, 1946 (Folder 17)
  - Conference on Racial Bigotry and New York Press, 1953 (Folder 18)
  - Conference on Radical Vocations in The White Community, 1967 (Folder 19)
  - Conference on Science and Technology in Israel and The Middle East, 1962 (Folder 20)
  - Conference on The Far East, 1946 (Folder 21)
  - Conference on The Impact of The Radical Right, 1962 (Folder 22)
  - Confluence (An International Forum), 1952-1953 (Folder 23)
  - Confrontation with Congress, 1969 (Folder 24)
  - Congo, 1963 (Folder 25)
  - Congregational Christian Churches, 1956-1963 (Box 161, Folder 1)
  - Congress of American Revolutionary Writers, 1935 (Folder 2)
  - Congress of American-Soviet Friendship, 1942-1943 (Folder 3)
  - Congress of American Women, 1945-1951 (Folder 4-5)
  - Congress of Freedom, undated (Folder 6)
  - Congress of Industrial Organizations (CIO), 1937-1975& undated
    - General Papers, 1937-1954 (Box 162, Folder 1-6)
    - General Papers, 1955-1975& undated (Box 163, Folder 1-3)
    - Clippings, 1940-1960 (Folder 4-6)
    - Conventions (11th - 14th), 1949-1952 (Box 164, Folder 1-7)
    - Publications:
      - Education Manual, 1952-1953 (Folder 8)
      - Pamphlets, 1937-1940s& undated (Folder 9)
      - Win-The -War Radio, 1942 (Folder 10)
  - Congress of Racial Equality (CORE) - Papers, 1946-1969& undated (Box 165, Folder 1-4)
  - The Congress of Scientists on Survival, 1963 (Box 166, Folder 1)
  - Congress of The United States, 1946-1948 (Folder 2)
  - Congress of Unrepresented People, 1965 (Folder 3)
  - Congress on Civil Rights, 1946 (Folder 4)
  - Congress View, 1945-1946 (Folder 5)
  - Congressional Committee on Un-American Activities, 1947 (Folder 6)
  - Congressional Digest, 1949 (Folder 7)
  - The Congressional Interns for Peace, 1967 (Folder 8)
  - Congressional Nominees, 1950 (Folder 9)
  - Congressional Peace Campaign Committee, 1968 (Folder 10)
  - Conlon Associates, LTD., 1959 (Folder 11)
  - Connecticut Artists' Protest, 1965 (Folder 12)
  - Connecticut Volunteers for Civil Rights, 1955-1960 (Folder 13)
  - Conscientious Resistance, 1967-1968 (Folder 14)
  - Conservative Almanac, undated (Folder 15)
  - Conservative Book Club, 1969-1972 (Folder 16)
  - Conservative Organizations, 1961-1962 (Folder 17)
  - Conservative Party of New York, 1971-1974 (Folder 18)
  - Conservative Republicans for The Defeat of Eisenhower, 1956 (Folder 19)
  - Conservative Society of America, 1964 (Folder 20)
  - Conservatives for Marchi, 1969 (Folder 21)
  - The Conspiracy, 1969 (Box 167, Folder 1-2)
  - Constitution Party, 1957-1964 (Folder 3)
  - Constitutional Education League, 1939-1948 (Folder 4-5)
  - Constitutional Education League, 1949-1958& undated (Box 168, Folder 1)
  - Constitutional Liberties Information Center, 1961-1966 (Folder 2)
  - Constitutional Rights Foundation, 1967 (Folder 3)
  - Constructive Action Inc., 1966 (Folder 4)
  - Consultative Conference on Desegregation, 1959 (Folder 5)
  - Consumer-Farmer Milk Cooperative, 1941 (Folder 6)
  - Consumer Lobby, 1967 (Folder 7)
  - Consumers' Research, Inc., 1936-1951 (Folder 8)
  - Consumers Union of U.S., Inc., 1939-1948 (Folder 9)
  - Contact, 1947 (Folder 10)
  - Contemporary Film, undated (Folder 11)
  - The Contemporary Reader, 1953 (Folder 12)
  - Contemporary School of Art, 1947 (Folder 13)
  - Contemporary Writers, 1947 (Folder 14)
  - Contempt Citations, 1949-1950 (Folder 15)
  - Continental Congress for Solidarity with Cuba, 1963 (Folder 16)
  - Continuation Committee of The Anti Imperialist-Equal Rights Congress, 1965 (Folder 17)
  - Contra Costa Committee Against The War in Vietnam, 1966-1967 (Folder 18)
  - The Convert, 1949 (Folder 19)
  - The Converted Catholic Magazine, 1949 (Folder 20)
  - Cook County Conference Against War and Fascism, 1953 (Folder 21)
  - Cooper Union, 1948-1951 (Box 169, Folder 1)
  - Cooperative Broadcasting Association, 1948 (Folder 2)
  - Cooperative for American Remittances to Europe, Inc., undated (Folder 3)
  - Cooperative School for Teachers, undated (Folder 4)
  - Coordinating Committee for Fundamental American Freedom, 1963 (Folder 5)
  - Coordinating Committee for Unemployment, undated (Folder 6)
  - Coordinating Committee to Lift The Embargo, 1939 (Folder 7)
  - Coplon-Gubitchev Espionage Case, 1949-1967 (Folder 8-9)
  - Cornell University Press, 1958 (Folder 10)
  - Coro Foundation, 1960 (Folder 11)
  - Correspondence: Re: $25,000 Salary Ceiling, 1942-1943 (Folder 12)
  - Correspondence School, 1951 (Folder 13)
  - The Correspondent, 1965 (Folder 14)
  - Correspondent for American-Chinese Friendship, 1959 (Folder 15)
  - Cortland's Fayette County Project, 1967 (Folder 16)
  - Cosmopolitan, 1950Contains information relating to the periodical, rather than copies of it. (Folder 17)
  - Cosmos Travel Bureau, Inc., 1957 (Folder 18)
  - Costa Rica, undated (Folder 19)
  - Council Against Communist Aggression, 1966-1970 (Box 170, Folder 1)
  - Council Against Intolerance in America, 1942-1954 (Folder 2)
  - Council for a Livable World, 1963-1970 (Folder 3)
  - Council for a Volunteer Military, 1967 (Folder 4)
  - Council for American Unity, 1960 (Folder 5)
  - Council for Citizens Action of Greater New York, 1945 (Folder 6)
  - Council for Civic Unity of San Francisco, 1957-1960 (Folder 7)
  - Council for Community Action, undated (Folder 8)
  - Council for Community Control, 1969 (Folder 9)
  - Council for Constitutional Liberties, 1961 (Folder 10)
  - Council for Democracy, 1941-1948 (Folder 11)
  - Council for Democracy in Greece, 1967 (Folder 12)
  - Council for Middle Eastern Affairs, Inc., 1957& undated (Folder 13)
  - Council for Pan American Democracy, 1938-1946& undated (Folder 14)
  - Council for Religion and The Homosexual, 1965 (Folder 15)
  - Council for The Advancement of The Americas, 1948-1962 (Folder 16)
  - Council for United Action, 1968 (Folder 17)
  - Council of American-Soviet Friendship, 1945 (Folder 18)
  - Council of Arts, Sciences, and Professions, 1953 (Folder 19)
  - Council of Concern of Soviet Jewry, 1968 (Folder 20)
  - Council of Federated Organizations, 1964-1965 (Folder 21)
  - Council of Greek Americans, 1952-1953 (Folder 22)
  - Council of Hollywood Guilds and Unions, 1944 (Folder 23)
  - Council of Social Agencies, 1946-1947 (Folder 24)
  - Council of U. S. Veterans, Inc., 1938 (Folder 25)
  - Council of Young Southerners, 1940 (Folder 26)
  - Council on African Affairs, 1942-1960 (Box 171, Folder 1-2)
  - Council on Books on Wartime, 1942 (Folder 3)
  - Council on Christian Social Progress, 1959 (Folder 4)
  - Council on Foreign Relations, 1946-1974 (Folder 5-6)
  - Council on Human Relations, 1959 (Folder 7)
  - Council on Religion and International Affairs, 1967-1970 (Folder 8)
  - Council on World Affairs, 1952-1958 (Folder 9)
  - Council on World Tensions, undated (Folder 10)
  - The Councilor, 1972 (Folder 11)
  - Counter-Action, 1948-1952 (Folder 12)
  - Counterattack, 1947-1952 (Box 172, Folder 1)
  - Counterpoint, 1969 (Folder 2)
  - Cousins for President Committee, 1967 (Folder 3)
  - Crabb, Lionel, 1956-1960 (Folder 4)
  - Cramer, Harold, 1969 (Folder 5)
  - Cranston, Alan, 1962 (Folder 6)
  - Cronin, John, Rev., 1962 (Folder 7)
  - The Cross and The Flag, 1948, Aug.-1960, Apr. (Folder 8-11)
  - The Cross and The Flag, 1960, May-1967, Aug. (Box 173, Folder 1-3)
  - Cross World Books and Periodicals, Inc., 1960-1968 (Folder 4)
  - Crosscurrents Press, Inc., 1960-1965 (Folder 5-6)
  - Crossroads, 1953 (Folder 7)
  - Crossword Puzzles, undated (Folder 8)
  - Crouch, Paul, 1949-1954 (Folder 9)
  - Crown Heights School of Catholic Workmen, undated (Box 174, Folder 1)
  - Crusade for Freedom, Inc., 1950-1968 (Folder 2)
  - The Crusader: Weekly Newsletter, 1960-1968 (Folder 3)
  - Crystal Lake Lodge, 1956-1965 (Folder 4)
  - Cuba, 1960-1968 (Folder 5-6)
  - Cuban-American Music Group, 1945 (Folder 7)
  - Cuban Crisis Advertisement Committee, 1962 (Box 175, Folder 1)
  - Cultural and Scientific Conference for World Peace, 1949 (Folder 2)
  - Cultural Committee of The Jewish Council, 1942 (Folder 3)
  - Cultural Research Action Project, 1969 (Folder 4)
  - Cultural Workers in Motion Pictures and Other Arts, 1949 (Folder 5)
  - Culture and Life, 1961 (Folder 6)
  - Current, 1960-1961 (Folder 7)
  - Current Affairs Press, 1963 (Folder 8)
  - The Current Digest of The Soviet Press, 1951 (Folder 9)
  - Current Soviet Documents, 1963-1964 (Folder 10-11)
  - Current Thought on Peace and War, 1961 (Folder 12)
  - Cutty Wren Records, 1967 (Folder 13)
  - Cvetic, Matt, 1951-1959 (Folder 14)
  - Cybertype Corporation, 1967 (Folder 15)
  - Czech Labor Union, 1947 (Folder 16)
  - Czechoslovak Industries Fair, 1949 (Folder 17)
  - Czechoslovak Life, 1949-1953 (Folder 18)
  - Czechoslovak Study Program, 1945-1947 (Folder 19)
  - Czechoslovakian Embassy, 1960 (Folder 20)
  - DM Digest, 1946 (Box 176, Folder 1)
  - Dade County News, undated (Folder 2)
  - Daedalus, 1966-1970 (Folder 3)
  - The Daily Compass, 1949-1954 (Folder 4-5)
  - Daily Labor News, 1952-1953 (Folder 6)
  - Daily Memoranda, 1950-1951 (Folder 7)
  - Daily Worker, 1928-1968& undated(See also The file for The Sunday edition of Daily Worker, The Worker) (Folder 8-9)
  - Daily World, 1967-1970 (Folder 10)
  - Dairy Farmers of America, 1958-1961 (Folder 11)
  - Dallas Council on World Affairs, 1957-1960 (Box 177, Folder 1-2)
  - Dance Congress and Festival, 1936-1937 (Folder 3)
  - Dance Observer, 1947-1948 (Folder 4)
  - Daniel De Leon League, 1969-1970 (Folder 5)
  - Dartmouth College, 1953-1969 (Folder 6)
  - Dartmouth Conferences, 1969 (Folder 7)
  - Daughters of Bilitis, 1959-1964 (Folder 8-9)
  - Daughters of The American Depression, 1940 (Folder 10)
  - Daughters of The American Revolution, 1935-1960 (Folder 11)
  - Davies, John P., 1952-1969 (Box 177A, Folder 1)
  - Davis. Angela, 1969-1970 (Folder 2)
  - Davis Defense Committee, 1954-1955 (Folder 3)
  - Davis, Elmer, 1945-1954 (Folder 4)
  - Davis, Jerome, 1950 (Folder 5)
  - Davis, Ossie, undated (Folder 6)
  - Davis, Rennard, 1968 (Folder 7)
  - Days of Protest, 1967 (Folder 8)
  - Dayton Area Coordinating Committee to End The War in Vietnam, 1966-1967 (Folder 9)
  - Dayton Committee for The Bill of Rights, 1967 (Folder 10)
  - Dayton Council on World Affairs, 1957-1960 (Folder 11)
  - Dayton Peace Committee, 1968 (Folder 12)
  - De Gregory Defense Committee, 1959-1961 (Folder 13)
  - De Lacy, Hugh, undated (Folder 14)
  - De Toledano, Ralph, 1953 (Folder 15)
  - De Velt, (The World), 1951 (Folder 16)
  - Deacons for Defense and Justice, 1965-1968 (Folder 17)
  - Dean, Vera Micheles, 1947 (Box 178, Folder 1)
  - Debs Youth School, 1937 (Folder 2)
  - December, 1965-1966 (Folder 3)
  - Declaration of Conscience, 1967 (Folder 4)
  - Defend Veterans Constitutional Rights Committee, 1956 (Folder 5)
  - The Defenders, 1964 (Folder 6)
  - Defenders of Furbearers, 1957 (Folder 7)
  - Defenders of The American Constitution, Inc., 1965-1972 (Folder 8)
  - Defenders of Three Against HUAC, 1965-1966& undated (Folder 9-10)
  - Defense Committee, 1970 (Box 179, Folder 1)
  - Defense Committee for Civil Rights for Communists, 1940-1941 (Folder 2)
  - Defense Committee for Jose Garcia & Antonia Sueiro, 1962-1963 (Folder 3)
  - Defense Committee for William L. Patterson, undated (Folder 4)
  - Defense Department, 1950 (Folder 5)
  - Defense for Freedom Committee, 1966 (Folder 6)
  - Defense Fund for Civil Rights, 1951 (Folder 7)
  - Defense Intelligence Agency, 1962-1969 (Folder 8)
  - Defense Intelligence School, 1963-1966 (Folder 9)
  - Defense of Communist Schools, 1948 (Folder 10)
  - Defense of Potash, Christoffel, and Bridges, 1950 (Folder 11)
  - Delany, Hubert, undated (Folder 12)
  - Delaware Valley Coalition, 1971-1974 (Folder 13)
  - Delaware Valley Communication Services, 1960 (Folder 14)
  - Dellinger, David, 1968 (Folder 15)
  - Democratic German Report, 1956-1965 (Folder 16)
  - Democratic Nationalist Party, 1959 (Folder 17)
  - Democratic Party, 1953-1970 (Folder 18-19)
  - Democratic Revolutionary Front, 1961 (Box 180, Folder 1)
  - Democratic Study Group, 1966-1969 (Folder 2)
  - Democrats, 1954 (Folder 3)
  - Democrats for Christenberry, undated (Folder 4)
  - Democrats for Peace, 1966 (Folder 5)
  - Democrats for Wallace Caucus, 1947 (Folder 6)
  - Demotte Galleries, undated (Folder 7)
  - Dennis, Eugene, 1949-1953 (Folder 8)
  - Dennis, Raymond, 1944-1950 (Folder 9)
  - Dennis, Lawrence, 1952 (Folder 10)
  - Denunciation of The Hartley Committee, 1949 (Folder 11)
  - Denver Post, 1956-1959 (Folder 12)
  - Denver Stop The War Committee, 1966 (Folder 13)
  - Department of Agriculture Survey, 1940-1946 (Folder 14)
  - Department of Health, Education, and Welfare, 1969 (Folder 15)
  - Department of Justice, 1954-1970 (Folder 16-17)
  - Department Stores Employees Union, 1937-1953 (Folder 18)
  - Deportation, 1947 (Folder 19)
  - Deriabin, Peter, 1959 (Folder 20)
  - Derounian, Arthur, 1943-1947 (Folder 21)
  - The Des Moines Register, 1960 (Folder 22)
  - Descendants of The American Revolution, undated (Folder 23)
  - Despite Everything, 1966-1967 (Folder 24)
  - Detention Camp Legislation, 1970-1971 (Folder 25)
  - Determined Ebony Council of Youth, 1968 (Box 181, Folder 1)
  - Detroit Coalition, 1969 (Folder 2)
  - Detroit Committee to End The War in Vietnam, 1965-1967 (Folder 3)
  - Detroit Police Department, 1937 (Folder 4)
  - Detroit Reception Committee for Soviet-Jewish Delegation, 1943 (Folder 5)
  - Devin-Adair Company, 1950 (Folder 6)
  - Devlin, Bernadette, 1969 (Folder 7)
  - Dewitt Clinton Youth and Adult Center, 1958 (Folder 8)
  - Dialetical Materialism, 1968 (Folder 9)
  - Dialetics, 1938 (Folder 10)
  - Dichter, Iwing, 1946-1952 (Folder 11)
  - Dickinson, Velvalee, 1945 (Folder 12)
  - Dies Committee: General Papers, 1938-1961& undated (Folder 13-14)
  - Dies Committee: Clippings, 1938-1942 (Box 182, Folder 1-3)
  - Dies Committee: References, undated (Folder 4)
  - Digest of The Soviet News, 1954 (Folder 5)
  - Digger Papers, 1969 (Folder 6)
  - Dilling, Elizabeth, 1944-1957& undated (Folder 7-9)
  - Dilworth Committee, 1951 (Box 183, Folder 1)
  - Dining Room Employees Union, undated (Folder 2)
  - Dinner to Wallace, 1949 (Folder 3)
  - Diplomat Hotel, 1970 (Folder 4)
  - Direction, 1937-1945 (Folder 5)
  - Directories, 1948-1969 (Folder 6-7)
  - Directory of Bulgarian Officials, 1963 (Folder 8)
  - Directory of Czechoslovak Officials, 1963 (Folder 9)
  - Directory of East German Officials, 1964 (Box 184, Folder 1)
  - Directory of Hungarian Officials, 1964 (Folder 2)
  - Directory of National and International Labor Unions, 1957-1959 (Folder 3)
  - Directory of Polish Officials, 1960 (Folder 4)
  - Disarmament, 1961-1963 (Folder 5)
  - Disarmament and The Cessation of Nuclear Weapons Tests, 1958 (Folder 6)
  - Discussion Bulletin, 1956-1957 (Folder 7)
  - Discussion Unlimited, Inc., 1963-1966 (Folder 8)
  - Dissent, 1956-1964 (Folder 9)
  - Dissent in The Army, 1970 (Box 185, Folder 1)
  - Dissenting Democrats, 1967 (Folder 2)
  - Distant Drummer, 1969 (Folder 3)
  - Distributive Workers Union, 1949-1970 (Folder 4-5)
  - Distributive, Processing, and Office Workers of America and District 65, A Short History ..., undated (Folder 6-8)
  - Distributive Trade Council of New York, 1948 (Box 186, Folder 1)
  - District of Columbia Area Non-Violent Action Group, 1960 (Folder 2)
  - District 65 Peace Action Committee, 1966 (Folder 3)
  - Djilas, Milovan, 1968 (Folder 4)
  - Doctors Loyalty Oath, undated (Folder 5)
  - Documents Processed, 1937-1965& undated (Folder 6)
  - Dodd, Bella, 1969 (Folder 7)
  - Dodge Revolutionary Union Movement, 1969 (Folder 8)
  - Dohrn, Bernadine, 1970 (Folder 9)
  - Dolan, Graham, 1950 (Folder 10)
  - Dolphin Center, Inc., 1971 (Folder 11)
  - Dominican Republic, 1960-1965 (Folder 12)
  - Dominican Revolutionary Party, 1968 (Folder 13)
  - Dominican Revolutionary Youth for Action, 1967 (Folder 14)
  - Donald G. Paterson Memorial Lectures, 1962 (Folder 15)
  - Donner, Frank, 1968 (Folder 16)
  - Doran, E. W., 1952 (Folder 17)
  - Dostal-Gass Defense Committee, 1969 (Folder 18)
  - Douglas, Kirk, 1948 (Folder 19)
  - Dover Publications, Inc., 1963 (Folder 20)
  - Down Draft, 1964 (Folder 21)
  - Downing, Oscar, 1950 (Folder 22)
  - Downtown Community School, 1946-1957 (Folder 23)
  - Draft Resistance, 1968-1969 (Folder 24)
  - Drake University, 1967 (Folder 25)
  - Dramatic Workshop Theater, undated (Folder 26)
  - Dressmakers Progressive Group, undated (Folder 27)
  - Dressmakers Rank and File Committee, undated (Folder 28)
  - Drew University, 1966 (Folder 29)
  - Drug and Hospital Employee Union, 1962 (Folder 30)
  - Drug Trade Salesmen Union, 1946 (Folder 31)
  - Dubois, Mrs., 1969 (Folder 32)
  - Dubois, W. E. B., undated (Folder 33)
  - (W. E. B.) Du Bois Clubs of America
    - Papers, 1956-1964 (Box 187, Folder 1-6)
    - Papers, 1965 (Box 188, Folder 1-6)
    - Papers, 1966, Jan.- July (Box 189, Folder 1-7)
    - Papers, 1966, Aug.- 1967, Dec. (Box 190, Folder 1-6)
    - Papers, 1968-1969& undated (Box 191, Folder 1-7)
  - Dull Brass, 1969 (Box 191-A, Folder 1)
  - Dulles, John Foster, 1942 (Folder 2)
  - Dump Lindsay, undated (Folder 3)
  - Dunn, Leslie Clarence, 1948 (Folder 4)
  - Duquesne, Frederick Joubert, 1941 (Folder 5)
  - Duran, Gustavo, 1951 (Folder 6)
  - Durkin, Henry P., 1967-1970 (Folder 7)
  - Dust Books, 1969 (Folder 8)
  - Dykes Simmons Freedom Fund, 1934-1966 (Folder 9)
  - Dylan, Bob, 1969 (Folder 10)
  - ELTA, 1956 (Box 192, Folder 1)
  - East Bay Committee for American Activities, 1953 (Folder 2)
  - East Bay Committee for Freedom in Education, 1959 (Folder 3)
  - East Coast Homophile Organization, 1964 (Folder 4)
  - East Europe and Soviet Russia, 1950-1953 (Folder 5)
  - East Harlem Tenants Council, 1967 (Folder 6)
  - East Midtown Committee for World Unity, undated (Folder 7)
  - Fort Side Community Congress, undated (Folder 8)
  - East Side Conference to Defend America- Crush Hitler, undated (Folder 9)
  - East Side Forum, 1967-1968 (Folder 10)
  - East Side Survival Organization, 1969 (Folder 11)
  - Rent Side Tenants Council, 1970 (Folder 12)
  - East Tenth Street Neighbors for Peace, 1968 (Folder 13)
  - East-West Association, 1948-1949 (Folder 14)
  - Eastern Sociological Society, 1950 (Folder 15)
  - Eastland Committee, 1953-1962 (Folder 16)
  - Economic Action for Peace, 1971 (Folder 17)
  - Economic Review of The Soviet Union, 1931-1934 (Folder 18)
  - Edge of The City, 1957 (Folder 19)
  - Editorial Publications, 1934 (Folder 20)
  - Education: (Box 193)
    - Antioch College, 1950-1969 (Folder 1)
    - Brooklyn College, 1952-1967 (Folder 2)
    - Brown University, 1961 (Folder 3)
    - Bryn Mawr, 1968-1971 (Folder 4)
    - Carleton College, 1961 (Folder 5)
    - Columbia University, 1951-1969 (Folder 6-7)
    - Cornell University, 1961-1969 (Folder 8)
    - Dartmouth College, 1961-1969 (Folder 9)
    - Howard University, 1940-1969 (Folder 10-11)
    - Johns Hopkins University, 1967 (Folder 12)
    - Morgan State College, 1965 (Folder 13)
    - New York Schools, 1941-1956 (Folder 14)
    - St. Louis University, 1966 (Box 194, Folder 1)
    - San Francisco State College, 1960-1969 (Folder 2)
    - Sarah Lawrence College, 1952-1957 (Folder 3)
    - Scarsdale, 19-54 (Folder 4)
    - The State University of New York at Buffalo, 1963-1964 (Folder 5)
    - Swarthmore College, 1960-1969 (Folder 6)
    - Teachers College, 1953 (Folder 7)
    - University of Maryland, 1960-1968 (Folder 8)
    - University of Oregon, 1964-1968 (Folder 9)
    - University of Virginia, 1963 (Folder 10)
    - University of Wisconsin, 1948-1969 (Folder 11-12)
    - Vassar College, 1967 (Folder 13)
    - Washington College, 1960 (Folder 14)
    - Wayne State University, 1961 (Folder 15)
    - Wilmington College, 1961 (Folder 16)
    - Yale University, 1952-1968 (Folder 17)
  - The Educational Reviewer, 1949-1969 (Box 195, Folder 1)
  - Edwards, Harvey, 1968 (Folder 2)
  - Edwards, James, 1948 (Folder 3)
  - Ehrenburg, Ilya, 1967 (Folder 4)
  - Ehilich, Paul, 1969 (Folder 5)
  - Eisenhower, Dwight, 1951 (Folder 6)
  - Eisenhower and The Little Red Schoolhouse, 1958 (Folder 7)
  - Eisler, Gerhart, 1946-1968 (Folder 8)
  - Eisler, Hans, undated (Folder 9)
  - Eldon Avenue Revolutionary Movement, 1954 (Folder 10)
  - Eldridge Cleaver Fund, 1969 (Folder 11)
  - Eleanor Roosevelt Peace Award Dinner, 1969 (Folder 12)
  - Eliscu, Edward, undated (Folder 13)
  - Elmhurst College, 1967 (Folder 14)
  - Elorac Books, 1969 (Folder 15)
  - Emanu-El Temple, 1961-1964 (Folder 16)
  - Embassy of The Polish People's Republic, 1960 (Folder 17)
  - Embassy of The U.S.S.R., 1952-1961 (Folder 18-19)
  - Embassy of The U.S.S.R., 1962-1969& undated (Box 196, Folder 1-2)
  - Emergency Citizens Committee to Save School Decentralization, 1968 (Folder 3)
  - Emergency Citizens Conference, 1946 (Folder 4)
  - Emergency Civil Liberties Committee, 1952-1967& undated (Folder 5-7)
  - Emergency Committee for Disaster Relief to Cuba, 1963-1964 (Box 197, Folder 1)
  - Emergency Committee for Indonesian Seamen, 1945 (Folder 2)
  - Emergency Committee for Southern Political Prisoners, undated (Folder 3)
  - Emergency Committee of Atomic Scientists, 1946-1948 (Folder 4)
  - Emergency Committee on Nigeria and Biafra, 1969 (Folder 5)
  - Emergency Committee on Rent and Housing, 1942-1968 (Folder 6)
  - Emergency Committee to Defend Liberties of Arizona Public Employers, 1961-1966 (Folder 7)
  - Emergency Conference Committee, undated (Folder 8)
  - Emergency Conference for Civilian Control of Atomic Energy, 1946 (Folder 9)
  - Emergency Conference on China and Saving The Peace, 1950 (Folder 10)
  - Emergency Conference to Save Rent Controls and Stop Rent Increases, 1946 (Folder 11)
  - Emergency Council on The Crisis in American Foreign Policy, 1966 (Folder 12)
  - Emergency Free Press Committee, 1956 (Folder 13)
  - Emergency National Conference Against Cambodia-Laos-Vietnam War, 1970 (Folder 14)
  - Emergency Peace Mobilization, 1940-1960 (Folder 15)
  - Emergency Refugee Conference, 1941 (Folder 16)
  - Emergency Relief Committee, 1938 (Folder 17)
  - Emergency Scholarship Fund, 1960 (Folder 18)
  - Emergency World People's Conference, 1947 (Folder 19)
  - Emma Lazarus Federation of Jewish Women Clubs, 1953-1969 (Folder 20)
  - Emmaus House, 1969-1970 (Folder 21)
  - Empire State Campaign Committee, undated (Folder 22)
  - Employees of United Cigar, undated (Folder 23)
  - Employer's Association of Chicago, 1948 (Folder 24)
  - Encampment for Citizenship, 1949-1964 (Folder 25-26)
  - Encounter, 1961 (Folder 27)
  - Encyclopaedia Britannica Films, 1954-1964 (Folder 28)
  - End Jim Crow in Baseball, 1945 (Folder 29)
  - End The Draft, 1962-1967 (Box 198, Folder 1-2)
  - End The War Committee, 1969 (Folder 3)
  - The Enemy Within Our Gates, 1919-1930& undated (Folder 4)